I was sitting with my friend Arthur Kornblum in a restaurant.
当时我正和我的朋友 Arthur Kornblum坐在餐厅里面
It was a Horn & Hardart cafeteria.
是一家Horn&Hardart自助餐厅
And this beautiful girl walked in, and I turned to Arthur
我看到这个漂亮的女孩走进来,我转向Arthur说
and I said "Arthur, you see that girl? I'm going to marry her."
"Arthur,你看到那个女孩了吗?我要娶她."
And two weeks later we were married.
两周以后我们结婚了
And it's over 50 years later,
到现在50多年过去了
and we're still married.
我们仍然是夫妻
UNIVERSITY OF CHICAGO - 1977
(芝加哥大学-1977年)
- I love you.
- 我爱你
Hi, Sally. Sally, this is Harry Burns.
嗨,Sally. Sally,这是Harry Burns
- Harry, this is Sally Albright. - Nice to meet you.
- Harry,这是Sally Albright - 很高兴认识你
- Wanna drive the first shift? - You're there already. You start.
- 你想先开一段吗? - 你已经在驾驶员位置了,你先开
Back's open.
尾箱打开了
- Call me. - I'll call you as soon as I get there.
- 给我打电话 - 我一到那就给你打
- Call me from the road. - I'll call you before that.
- 在路上就打 - 我会在那之前打
- I love you.
- 我爱你
Sorry.
不好意思
- I miss you already. I miss you already. - I miss you.
- 我已经在想你了,我已经在想你了 - 我也想你
- Bye.
- 拜拜
I have it all figured out. It's an 18-hour trip, which becomes six shifts of three hours.
我已经算过了,一共18小时的车程 分成6段,我们3小时轮换一次驾驶
Or, alternatively, we could break it down by mileage.
或者我们也可以按里程来分
There's a... There's a map on the visor
遮阳板上面有张地图
that I've marked to show the locations where we can change shifts.
我已经标记好了我们交换驾驶的地点
Grape?
吃葡萄吗?
No. I don't like to eat between meals.
不,我不喜欢在正餐之间吃东西
I'll roll down the window.
我会摇下车窗
Why don't you tell me the story of your life?
为什么不给我讲讲你的故事?
- The story of my life? - We got 18 hours to kill before New York.
- 我的故事? - 到纽约前我们得打发18个小时呢
That won't even get us out of Chicago. Nothing's happened to me yet.
不出芝加哥我的故事就会讲完的 我没有多少故事
- So I'm going to New York. - So something'll happen?
- 所以我才要去纽约 - 然后就会发生些什么?
- Yes. - Like what?
- 是的 - 比如?
Like I'm going to journalism school.
比如我要去读新闻学校,成为记者
So you can write about things that happen to other people.
这样你就可以写别人的故事了
- That's one way to look at it. - Suppose nothing happens.
- 也可以这样说 - 假设什么都没有发生
Suppose you never meet anybody, you never become anything,
假设你从来没有遇到任何人 也没有成为什么人
then you die and nobody notices for two weeks until the smell drifts into the hall.
然后你无人问津的死去直到两周后 尸体的气味飘出来才被发现
- Amanda said you had a dark side. - That's what drew her to me.
- Amanda说你有阴暗的一面 - 这就是我吸引她的地方
- Your dark side? - Sure. Why, don't you have a dark side?
- 你的阴暗? - 没错.怎么,你没有阴暗的一面吗?
I know, you probably dot your "i"s with little hearts.
我想也许你只是不像平常人一样有阴暗的一面
I have just as much of a dark side as the next person.
我和其他人一样有阴暗的一面
Oh, really? When I buy a new book, I always read the last page first.
哦,是吗?我买了新书总是先看最后一页
That way, if I die before I finish I know how it ends.
这样的话如果我在看完这本书前 死去我就能知道结局是什么了
That, my friend, is a dark side.
看,我的朋友,这才是阴暗
That doesn't mean you're deep. I mean, yes, basically I'm a happy person.
这不代表你有多高深,我是说, 基本上我是个很乐观的人
- So am I. - I don't see anything wrong with that.
- 我也是 - 我不认为这有什么不对
No, you're too busy being happy. Ever think about death?
不,你太热衷于乐观了 想过死亡吗?
- Yes. - Sure you do. A fleeting thought
- 是的 - 当然你想过.闪过脑海的感觉
that drifts in and out of the transom of your mind. I spend days.
我可是花费了数小时,数天去想
And this makes you a better person?
这样你就能变得更好了?
Look, when the shit comes down, I'm gonna be prepared and you're not.
当大限来临的时候我已经准备好了而你没有
In the meantime, you're gonna ruin your whole life waiting for it.
而你会因为等待大限到来毁了你的生活
- You're wrong. - I'm not wrong. He wants her to leave.
- 你错了 - 我没错,他想让她走
- That's why he puts her on the plane. - She doesn't want to stay!
- 这就是为什么他让她上了飞机 - 我不认为她想留下来了
Of course she wants to stay! Wouldn't you rather be with Bogart than the other guy?
她当然想留下来.你不是也想和Bogart在一起吗?
I don't wanna spend my life in Casablanca married to a man who runs a bar.
我不想一辈子呆在卡萨布兰卡, 和一个开酒吧的结婚
That probably sounds snobbish to you, but I don't.
也许你认为这样很势利,但是我不这样想
- You'd rather be in a loveless marriage... - And First Lady of Czechoslovakia.
- 你愿意过毫无激情的婚姻生活... - 还有捷克斯洛伐克的第一夫人
..than with the man you had the greatest sex of your life with,
也不愿和你有过一生最棒性经历的人在一起
just because he owns a bar and that is all he does?
只是因为他是开酒吧的,而且只是开酒吧的?
Yes.
是的
And so would any woman in her right mind. Women are practical,
清醒的女人都会这样想的.女人很实际
even Ingrid Bergman, which is why she gets on the plane at the end of the movie.
就算是英格利?褒曼,都在电影的结尾上了飞机
I understand.
我明白了
- What? What? - Nothing.
- 什么? 什么? - 没什么
- What? - Forget about it.
- 什么? - 算了吧
- Forget about what? - It's not important.
- 什么算了吧? - 这不重要
No, just tell me.
不,你直说吧
Obviously you haven't had great sex yet.
很明显你没有过很棒的性经历
- Two, please. - Right over there.
- 麻烦你,两位 - 那边有空位
- Yes, I have. - No, you haven't.
- 不对,我有过 - 不,你没有过
It just so happens that I have had plenty of good sex.
可实际是我有过很多很棒的性经历
With whom?
和谁?
- What? - With whom did you have this great sex?
- 什么? - 和谁有过很棒的性经历?
I'm not gonna tell you that!
我才不会告诉你呢
Fine. Don't tell me.
好吧,不要告诉我
- Shel Gordon. - Shel. Sheldon?
- Shel Gordon. - Shel. Sheldon?
No. No, you did not have great sex with Sheldon.
不,不,你不会和Sheldon有很棒的性经历
- I did, too. - No, you didn't.
- 我有过 - 不,你没有
A Sheldon can do your taxes. If you need a root canal, Sheldon's your man.
Sheldon可以帮你报税. 如果你需要钱,Sheldon也可以帮你
But humpin' is not Sheldon's strong suit. It's the name.
不过那种事Sheldon并不在行,因为他的名字
"Do it to me, Sheldon." "You're an animal, Sheldon." "Ride me, big Sheldon."
"上啊,Sheldon","你是野兽,Sheldon" "来吧,Sheldon"
- It doesn't work. - Hi.
- 这样不行 - 嗨
- What can I get you? - I'll have a number three.
- 要点些什么? - 我要一个3号餐
The chef's salad with the oil and vinegar on the side. And the apple pie ?la mode.
我要主厨沙拉,油醋另放,还有苹果派
Chef and apple ?la mode.
主厨沙拉苹果派
But I'd like the pie heated and I want the ice cream on the side.
派要加热,冰淇淋放在旁边
I'd like strawberry, if you have it. If not, then whipped cream, but only if it's real.
如果有的话还要草莓. 如果没有就要搅打过的奶油,当然得是天然的
If it's out of a can, nothing.
如果是罐装的,那就算了
- Not even the pie? - No, just the pie, but then not heated.
- 派也不要了吗? - 不,只要派,不过不要热的.
- What? - Nothin'. Nothin'.
- 怎么? - 没什么,没什么.
- How come you broke up with Sheldon? - How do you know we broke up?
- 你为什么和Sheldon分手 - 你怎么知道我们分手了?
If you didn't, you wouldn't be with me. You'd be with Shel the Wonder Schlong.
如果没有,你不会跟我而是 和Sheldon来共渡这次美妙的旅行
First of all, I am not with you.
首先,我没有跟着你
And second of all, it is none of your business why we broke up.
其次,我们分手的事和你无关
You're right, you're right. I don't wanna know.
没错,没错,我不想知道
Well, it was because he was jealous and I had these days-of-the-week underpants.
是因为他嫉妒心很重, 而且我喜欢穿七彩内裤
Sorry, I need a judge's ruling on this.
抱歉,我需要把这个问清楚
- Days-of-the-week underpants? - Yes.
- 七彩内裤? - 是的
They had days of the week on them and I thought they were funny.
是每天不同颜色的我觉得很有趣
Then one day Sheldon says to me "You never wear Sunday."
然后有一天Sheldon对我说:"你周日从来不穿."
He's all suspicious. Where had I left Sunday?
他很奇怪,为什么周日不穿?
And I told him and he didn't believe me.
我告诉他原因他却不相信我
- What? - They don't make Sunday.
- 是什么? - 他们没有做周日的颜色
- Why not? - Because of God.
- 为什么? - 因为上帝
OK, so 15 % of my share is 90.
OK,我付15%是90美分
$6.90.
6美圆90美分
Let's leave seven.
我们付7圆
What?
怎么了?
Do I have something on my face?
我脸上有东西?
You're a very attractive person.
你是个很迷人的人
Thank you.
谢谢
Amanda never said how attractive you were.
Amanda从没说过你有多迷人
Maybe she doesn't think I'm attractive.
也许她不觉得我迷人吧
I don't think it's a matter of opinion. Empirically, you are attractive.
我不认为这还需要讨论.依我看你就是很迷人
Amanda is my friend.
Amanda是我的朋友
So?
所以?
- So you're going with her. - So?
- 而且你是她男朋友 - 所以?
So you're coming on to me!
而你现在在纠缠我
No, I wasn't.
不,我没有
What?
怎么了?
Can't a man say a woman is attractive without it being a come-on?
男人不能对女人说她很迷人而不纠缠她吗?
All right, all right.
好吧,好吧
Let's just say, just for the sake of argument, that it was a come-on.
我们说清楚,只是为了说清楚,就算是纠缠吧
What d'you want me to do about it? I take it back, OK? I take it back.
你想让我怎么办?我收回,是吧?我收回
You can't take it back.
你不能收回
- Why not? - Because it's already out there.
- 为什么不能? - 因为你已经那样做了
What are we supposed to do? Call the cops, it's already out there!
那我们怎么办?叫警察吗?事情已经发生了
Just let it lie.
就当没发生过
- OK? - Great! "Let it lie." That's my policy.
- 好吗? - 很好,"当没发生过",正是我的作风
That's what I always say: "Let it lie."
我总是说:"就当没发生过."
Wanna spend the night in a motel?
想在汽车旅馆过夜吗?
- See? I didn't let it lie. - Harry.
- 看到了?我没有当成没发生 - Harry.
I said I would, then I didn't.
我说我会,但我没那样
- Harry! - What?
- Harry! - 怎么?
We are just going to be friends, OK?
我们只做朋友,好吗?
Great! Friends! It's the best thing.
太好了,朋友,再好不过了
You realise that we could never be friends.
你意识到我们永远成不了朋友
- Why not? - What I'm saying is,
- 为什么? - 我想说的是...
and this is not a come-on in any way, shape or form,
这些话没有任何纠缠的意思
is that men and women can't be friends, cos the sex part always gets in the way.
男人和女人无法成为朋友, 因为总是会有性的问题掺杂进来
That's not true. I have a number of men friends and there is no sex involved.
不是这样的.我有很多不涉及到性关系的男性朋友
- You don't. - I do.
- 你没有 - 我有
- I do!
- 我有!
You only think you do.
你只是认为你有
I have sex with them without my knowledge?
我和他们有了性关系而我自己不知道?
No, they all wanna have sex with you.
不,他们都想和你发生性关系
- They do not. - Do, too.
- 他们不想 - 他们想
How do you know?
你怎么知道?
No man can be friends with a woman he finds attractive.
男人无法和他认为迷人的女人成为朋友
He always wants to have sex with her.
他总是想和她发生性关系
So you're saying a man can be friends with a woman he finds unattractive.
你认为男人无法和他认为迷人的女人成为朋友
No, you pretty much wanna nail them, too.
是的,你会很想得到她们
What if they don't wanna have sex?
如果她们不想发生性关系呢?
Doesn't matter. The sex thing is already out there, so the friendship is doomed.
那也没关系.性的事情已经露出苗头了 朋友关系没戏了
- I guess we're not gonna be friends then. - Guess not.
- 我想我们不会成为朋友的 - 我也这样想
That's too bad.
真可惜
You were the only person that I knew in New York.
你是我在纽约唯一认识的一个人
- Thanks for the ride. - Yeah. It was interesting.
- 谢谢你让我搭车 - 这很有意思
- It was nice knowing you. - Yeah.
- 很高兴认识了你 - 是的
- Well, have a nice life. - You, too.
- 那么,祝你生活愉快 - 你也一样
- We fell in love in high school. - Yeah, we were high-school sweethearts.
- 我们在高中就相爱了 - 是的,我们是高中情侣
But then after our junior year his parents moved away.
不过在第二学年的时候他搬家了
- But I never forgot her. - He never forgot me.
- 但是我从来没有忘记她 - 他从没忘记我
No, her face was burned on my brain.
从没,她的样子印在我的脑中
And it was 34 years later that I was walking down Broadway
过了34年,我从百老汇经过
and I saw her come out of Toffenetti's.
我看到她从Toffenetti店走出来
We both looked at each other,
我们都看着对方
and it was just as though not a single day had gone by.
就像岁月从来没有流逝过一样
She was just as beautiful as she was at sixteen.
她依旧像她16岁时那么漂亮
He was just the same.
他也没有变
He looked exactly the same.
他看起来一点都没变
FIVE YEARS LATER
(5年后)
Joe! I thought it was you. I thought it was you.
Joe! 我就知道是你,我就知道
- Harry Burns. - Harry. How ya doin'?
- Harry Burns. - Harry.近况如何?
- Good. How you doin'? - Fine. I'm doin' fine.
- 很好,你呢? - 很好,我很好
I was just walking by and I thought it was you.
我正好经过,看到好像是你
Yeah, it was.
是的,是我
- You still with the DA's office? - No, I switched to the other side. You?
- 你还在数据分析部门吗? - 不,我换到其他部门了.你呢?
I work with a small firm. We do political consulting. Yeah, it's great.
我在一家小公司工作.我们做政治咨询,还不错
Harry, this is Sally Albright. Harry Burns.
Harry,这是Sally Albright. Harry Burns.
Harry and I, we used to... We lived in the same building.
Harry和我曾经住在同一座公寓里面
Well, listen, I got a plane to catch. It was good to see you, Joe. Bye.
是这样,我得去赶飞机了 很高兴见到你,Joe,再见
Thank God he couldn't place me. I drove to New York with him five years ago
谢天谢地他没认出我来 5年前我曾经和他一起开车去纽约
and it was the longest night of my life.
那真是我有生以来最长的一个晚上
- What happened? - He made a pass at me. When I said no:
- 出了什么事情? - 他想要纠缠我.被我拒绝...
he was going with a girlfriend of mine...
他那时正和我一个朋友交往
Oh, God. I can't remember her name.
哦,天啊,我想不起来她的名字了
Don't get involved with me. I am 26 and can't remember the name of the girl
别和我交往下去了.我26了, 而且想不起来我好朋友的名字...
I was such good friends with I wouldn't get involved with her boyfriend.
那个我不愿和她男朋友有牵扯的好朋友的名字
- So what happened? - When?
- 结果发生了什么? - 什么?
When he made a pass, you said no...
他纠缠你,你说不的时候...
I said we could just be friends.
我说他只是朋友
And this part I remember. He said men and women could never really be friends.
我记得那一幕.他说男人和女人 永远成不了真正的朋友
Do you think that's true?
你认为他说的对吗?
No.
不对
Do you have any women friends, just friends?
你有女性朋友吗?只是朋友?
No.
没有
But I will get one if it's important to you.
不过如果这对你很重要那我会找一个
Amanda Reese!
Amanda Reese!
That was her name. Thank God.
她的名字,谢天谢地
I will miss you. I love you.
我会想你的,我爱你
- You do? - Yes.
- 你会吗? - 是的
I love you.
我爱你
- What would you like to drink? - Nothing, thanks.
- 要喝点什么吗? - 不用了,谢谢
- D'you have any Bloody Mary mix? - Yes.
- 有血腥玛丽吗? - 有
No, wait. Here's what I want. Regular tomato juice, fill it up three quarters,
是这样.我要4分之3杯普通的番茄汁
then add a splash of Bloody Mary mix - just a splash - and some lime on the side.
再加上一点点血腥玛丽,只要一点点. 再加上一片酸橙
The University of Chicago, right?
芝加哥大学,对吧?
- Yes. - Did you look this good at university?
- 是的 - 你在大学的时候也这么漂亮吗?
- No. - Did we ever...?
- 不 - 我们是不是...?
No. No!
没有,没有!
We drove from Chicago to New York together after graduation.
毕业典礼后我们一起从芝加哥开车去的纽约
- Would you two like to sit together? - Great! Thank you.
- 你们想坐在一起吗? - 太好了,谢谢
You were a good friend of...
你是...的好朋友...
Amanda's. I can't believe you can't remember her name.
Amanda.真不敢相信你忘记了她的名字
What do you mean? I can remember. Amanda Rice.
什么意思?我记得,Amanda Rice
- Reese. - Reese, right. What happened to her?
- Reese. - Reese,是的.她现在怎么样?
- I have no idea. - You have no idea?!
- 我不知道 - 你不知道?
You were friends. We didn't make it because you were such good friends.
你们是朋友.我们没有发生关系 因为你们那时是很好的朋友
- You went with her! - Was it worth it?
- 你正在和她交往! - 那值得吗?
The sacrifice, for a friend you no longer see?
为了一个长时间没联系的朋友作出牺牲
Harry, you might not believe this,
Harry,你可能不会相信这个
but I never considered not sleeping with you a sacrifice.
不过我从来没有认为不和你上床是牺牲
Fair enough. Fair enough.
说得好,说得好
- You wanted to be a gymnast. - Journalist.
- 你想成为体育专家 - 新闻记者
- That's what I said. And? - I am a journalist. I work at The News.
- 我就是那意思.结果呢? - 我现在就是个新闻记者.在《The News》工作
Great. And you're with Joe.
很好.你和Joe在交往
Well, that's great. Great.
那真是太好了,很好
You're together, what, three weeks?
你们交往多久了,3星期?
- A month. How did you know? - You take someone to the airport,
- 一个月.你怎么知道的? - 送一个人到机场,
it's the beginning of a relationship. That is why I never do that at the beginning.
是交往刚开始的关系.这就是为什么 我从来不在开始交往时去机场送人
- Why? - Because eventually things move on
- 为什么? - 因为随着事情的进展
and you don't take someone. I never wanted anyone to say
你不去送了.我不想听到别人说:
"How come you never take me to the airport any more?"
"为什么你再也不送我去机场了?"
It's amazing. You look normal, but actually you are the Angel of Death.
这很不可思议.你看上去是个正常人 而实际上你是死亡天使
Are you gonna marry him?
你想和他结婚吗?
We have known each other a month and neither of us wants to marry right now.
我们才认识1个月,而且现在我们都还不想结婚
I'm getting married.
我要结婚了
You are?
是吗?
- You are? - Yeah.
- 你要结婚了? - 是的
- Who is she? - Helen Hillson. She's keeping her name.
- 和谁? - Helen Hillson.她是律师,她不会冠夫姓
- You're getting married. - Yeah.
- 你要结婚了 - 是的
What's so funny about that?
这有什么好笑的?
It's just... It's just so optimistic of you, Harry.
只是....只是对你来说这太乐观了,Harry
You'd be amazed what falling madly in love can do for you.
如果你知道了疯狂的爱上一个人你 会对你产生什么影响一定会觉得很神奇
Well, it's wonderful. It's nice to see you embracing life.
这很好.很高兴看到你开始拥抱生活了
Yeah. Plus, you get to a certain point where you get tired of the whole thing.
是的,而你终于到了对一切感到厌烦的时候了
- What whole thing? - The whole "life of a single guy" thing.
- 什么一切? - 单身生活的一切
You meet someone, you have the safe lunch, you decide to move on to dinner.
你认识某个人,经过试探性的约会 你决定开始正式约会了
You go dancing, you do the white man's overbite,
你们去跳舞,像白人那样咬着嘴唇跳舞
go back to her place, have sex, and then you know what goes through your mind?
去她家,做爱,然后你就知道真正想的是什么了?
"How long do I have to lie here and hold her before I can go home?"
"在我回家前我要躺在这里抱她多久?"
"Is 30 seconds enough?"
"30秒钟够长吗?"
That's what you're thinking? Is that true?
这就是你所想的,是真的吗?
Sure. All men think that.
没错,所有的男人都这样想
How long do you like to be held afterwards? All night, right?
你希望被抱多久呢?整夜,对吗?
That's the problem. Somewhere between 30 seconds and all night is your problem.
这就是问题所在.30秒到整夜之间就是你的问题.
- I don't have a problem. - Yeah, you do.
- 我没有这样的问题 - 是的,你有
- Staying over? - Yes.
- 要过夜吗? - 是的
Would you like to have dinner? Just friends.
想一起吃饭吗?朋友关系的
You don't believe men and women can be friends.
你说男人和女人成不了朋友
- When did I say that? - On the ride to New York.
- 我什么时候说过的? - 在去纽约的路上
No, no, no, no, I never said that.
不,不,不,不,我从来没说过
Yes, that's right. They can't be friends.
是的,没错.成不了朋友
Unless both are involved with someone. Then they can. I amend the earlier rule.
除非你们都在和其他人在交往,就没事了 我修正我以前的规则
If two people are in relationships, the pressure of possible involvement is lifted.
如果两个人都各自在交往, 那么可能产生关系的压力就没有
That doesn't work either. The person you're with can't see
不过这样也不行.和你交往的人不能明白...
why you need to be friends with the person,
为什么你要和他成为朋友...
like it means something is missing from the relationship.
就好像是两个人的关系中少了些什么
Then when you say "No, nothing is missing", the person you're with
那么当你说:"没有,没有少什么" 和你交往的人就会指责...
accuses you of being attracted to the person you're just friends with,
你被那个你想交朋友的人吸引了...
which you probably are. I mean, let's face it.
也许真的是这样.我是说,面对这一切吧
So we're back to the rule before the amendment:
现在我们回到被修改之前的原则上:
men and women can't be friends. Where's it leave us?
男人和女人不能成为朋友. 那么还剩下什么呢?
- Harry. - What?
- Harry. - 什么?
Goodbye.
再见
OK.
好的
I'll just stop walking. I'll let you go ahead.
我停来下来好了.让你先走
We were married 40 years ago.
我们40年前结的婚
We were married three years, we got a divorce. Then I married Marjorie.
在我们结婚3年时,我们离婚了. 然后我娶了Marjorie
- First you lived with Barbara. - Right, Barbara.
- 最开始你和Barbara同居 - 是的,Barbara
But I didn't marry Barbara. I married Marjorie.
但是我没有娶Barbara,我娶了Marjorie
- Then you got a divorce. - Right. Then I married Katie.
- 然后你离婚了 - 是的.然后我娶了Katie
Another divorce.
再次离婚
Then a couple of years later at Eddie Collecio's funeral, I ran into her.
几年后在Eddie Collecio的葬礼上我遇见她
I was with some girl I don't even remember.
我正和我连名字都不记得的女孩在一起
- Roberta. - Right. Roberta.
- Roberta. - 是的.Roberta.
But I couldn't take my eyes off you.
但是我的视线无法从你身上移开
I remember I snuck over to her and I said...
我记得我偷偷溜到她身旁说:
- What did I say? - You said "What are you doin' after?"
- 我说了什么? - 你说:"结束后你要干什么?"
Right. So I ditch Roberta, we go for coffee, a month later we're married.
是的.因此我丢下Roberta,我们去了咖啡店 一个月以后我们结婚了
35 years to the day after our first marriage.
正是我们第一次结婚35年后的那天
- I went through his pockets. - Marie, why?
- 我检查了他的口袋 - Marie,为什么?
FIVE YEARS LATER
(五年后)
- You know what I found? - No, what?
- 你知道我找到了什么吗? - 不知道,是什么?
They just bought a dining-room table. His wife just spent $1 ,600 on a table.
他们刚刚买了张餐桌. 他妻子刚刚花了1600美圆买了张餐桌
- Where? - The point isn't where, Alice.
- 在哪儿买的? - 重点不是在哪里买的,Aliece
The point is he's never gonna leave her.
重点在与他根本不打算离开她
What else is new? You've known this for two years.
有什么不一样吗?这你2年前就知道了
You're right. I know you're right.
你说得对，我知道你说得对
Can't you find someone single? When I was single I knew lots of nice single men.
你就找不到一个单身的吗? 我单身时认识很多单身的好男人
There must be someone. Sally found someone.
肯定还有的.Sally就找到了一个
Sally got the last good one.
Sally找到了最后一个好男人
- Joe and I broke up. - What?
- 我的Joe分手了 - 什么?
- When? - Monday.
- 什么时候? - 周一
- You waited three days? - Joe's available?
- 你等了3天才说? - Joe现在单身了?
For God's sake, Marie, don't you have feelings? She's obviously upset.
拜托,Marie,你是冷血吗?她显然很难过
I'm not that upset. We'd been growing apart for a while.
我没有那么难过.我们已经冷淡了一段时间了
But you were a couple.
但是你们曾经是天水一对
You had someone to go places with. You had a date on national holidays!
你有可以陪你出去的人. 你在国庆节约会
I said to myself "You deserve more than this. You're 31 ..."
我对自己说:"你应该得到更好的,你31岁..."
- And the clock is ticking. - No, it doesn't start to tick until you're 36.
- 青春之钟一直在滴答的响 - 不,到了36岁它才会开始响
God, you're in such great shape.
天啊,你的状况还是那么的好
Well, I've had a few days to get used to it, and I feel OK.
我用了几天时间来适应,现在我感觉很好
Good. Then you're ready.
很好,那你已经准备好了
- Really, Marie! - Well, how else do you think you do it?
- 拜托,Marie! - 不然你觉得应该怎么办?
I've got the perfect guy. I don't find him attractive, but you might.
我找到了一个完美的人 我并不觉得他迷人，但也许你会
She doesn't have a problem with chins.
她对于下巴的问题不介意
- Marie, I'm not ready yet. - But you just said you were over him.
- Marie,我还没准备好呢 - 不过你刚刚说过你对他没感觉了
I am over him, but I'm in a mourning period.
我是对他没感觉了,不过我还在哀悼期
- Who is it? - Alex Anderson.
- 那是谁? - Alex Anderson
You fixed me up with him six years ago.
6年前你就打算撮合我们了
Sorry. God.
抱歉,天啊
All right, wait. Here. Here we go.
好吧,等下,这个,看看这个
- Ken Darman. - He's been married for over a year.
- Ken Darman. - 他已经结婚了1年了
Really?
是吗?
Married.
已婚
- Wait. Wait, I got one. - Look,
- 等下,等下,我找到一个 - 是这样...
there is no point going out with someone I might like if I met him at the right time,
现在与任何人交往都没有意义 除非我们在合适的时机相识
but who right now would just be a transitional man.
但是现在的任何人都只会算是过渡
OK, but don't wait too long. Remember what happened with David Warsaw?
好吧,但是不要等太久了. 记得发生在Daivd Warsaw身上的事吧
His wife left him and everyone said "Give him some time. Don't move in too fast."
他的妻子离开了他然后所有人都说: "给他点时间,不要逼他太紧"
Six months later he was dead.
6个月后他死了
Are you saying I should marry quickly in case he's about to die?
你是说我应该很快结婚以防他会死去?
At least you could say you were married.
至少你能说你已经结过婚了
I'm saying that the right man is out there. If you don't grab him, someone else will,
我是想说合适的人或许就在那 如果你不抓住机会,别人也会
and you'll spend your life knowing that someone else is married to your husband.
然后你会用一辈子时间明白是 别人嫁给了你的丈夫
Ten! Hut!
Ten! Hut!
- When did this happen? - Friday. Helen comes home from work
- 什么时候的事情? - 周五.Helen下班回家...
and she says "I don't know if I wanna be married any more."
她说:"我不知道还想不想和你维持这段婚姻."
Like it's the institution. Nothing personal, just something she's been thinking about.
就像在事务所，好像事不关己 只是件她不经意想起的事情
I'm calm. I say "Why don't we take time to think about it? Don't rush into anything."
我很冷静,我说:"为什么我们不花点时间考虑下? 什么事都不该太急."
- Yeah, right. - Next day she says she's thought about it.
- 是的,没错 - 第二天她说她想过了
She wants a trial separation. She just wants to try it.
她想试着分居一下.只是试试看
But we can still date - like this is supposed to cushion the blow.
但是我们还是可以约会 就像这是缓冲期一样
I got married so I could stop dating, so still dating is not a big incentive
我结婚是为了不用再约会, 所以继续约会不是什么好事
since the last thing you wanna do is date your wife, who should love you.
既然最后你想做的事情是 约会本应爱着你的妻子
Which is what I'm saying to her, when it occurs to me maybe she doesn't.
这就是我对她说的,也许她不爱我了
So I say to her "Don't you love me any more?"
所以我问她:"你不再爱我了吗?"
D'you know what she says? "I don't know if I've ever loved you."
你知道她说了什么吗? "我不知道我是否爱过你."
That's harsh. You don't bounce back from that right away.
太无情了.你不能立即让步
- Thanks, Jess. - No, I'm a writer. I know dialogue.
- 谢谢你,Jess - 不,我是个作家,我熟悉对话
That's particularly harsh.
那话明显是很无情的
Then she says someone in her office is going to South America
然后她告诉我她有个同事要去南部
and she can sublet his apartment. I can't believe this. And the doorbell rings.
她可以转租她的公寓 难以置信,接着门铃响了
"I can sublet his apartment" - the words still hang in the air like in a balloon...
"她可以转租她的公寓"这句话还在 空气中盘旋像一个挂在嘴上的气球
- Like a cartoon. - Right.
- 像卡通那样 - 没错
So I go to the door and there are moving men there. Now I start to get suspicious.
我去开门门口站了个搬运工 现在我开始怀疑了
I say "Helen, when did you call these movers?" She doesn't say anything.
我说:"Helen,你什么时候叫的搬运工?" 她什么都没说
So I ask the movers "When did this woman book you?"
于是我问搬运工:"她什么时候预约的?"
And they're three huge guys. One with a T-shirt saying "Don't fuck with Mr Zero."
一共3个大块头.其中一个穿T恤的说: "别开Mr Zero的玩笑."
So I said "Helen, when did you make this arrangement?" She says "A week ago."
我问:"Helen,你是什么时候安排的?" 她说:"一周前."
I said "You've known for a week and you didn't tell me?"
我说:"一周前你就决定了却没有告诉我?"
And she says "I didn't wanna ruin your birthday."
她说:"我不想毁了你的生日."
Mr Zero knew you were getting a divorce a week before you?
Mr Zero都比你早一周知道你要离婚了
- Mr Zero knew. - I can't believe this!
- Mr Zero知道 - 我不敢相信
- I haven't told you the bad part yet. - What's worse than Mr Zero knowing?
- 我还没告诉你最糟糕的部分呢 - 还有什么比Mr Zero先知道糟糕的?
It's all a lie.
全是谎言
She's in love with somebody else. Some tax attorney.
她爱上了别人.一个税务律师
- She moved in with him. - How did you find out?
- 她搬去和他住了 - 你怎么发现的?
I followed her. Stood outside the building.
我跟踪了她.站在他的屋外
- That's so humiliating! - Tell me about it.
- 真是羞愧难当 - 和我说说吧
And, you know, I knew. I knew that even though we were happy, it was an illusion.
你知道,我明白了: 我认为我们快乐都只是幻觉
And that one day she'd kick the shit outta me.
那天她打破了我的幻觉
Marriages don't break up due to infidelity. It's a symptom something else is wrong.
婚姻不会因外遇而破裂. 显然是其他地方出了问题
Oh, really? Well, that symptom is fucking my wife!
是吗?那出问题的肯定是我老婆
So I just happened to see his American Express bill.
我不小心看到了他的美国运通帐单
What do you mean "just happened" to see it?
"不小心"是什么意思?
Well, he was shaving, and there it was in his briefcase.
他正在刮胡子,帐单在他的公文包里
What if he came out and saw you?
如果他出来看到了怎么办?
You're missing the point. I'm telling you what I found.
这不是重点.我在告诉你我找到了什么
He just spent $1 20 on a new nightgown for his wife.
他刚花了120美圆给他妻子买了件新睡衣
- I don't think he's ever gonna leave her. - No one thinks he's ever gonna leave her.
- 我不认为他想离开她 - 没有人认为他想离开她
You're right, you're right. I know you're right.
没错,没错,我知道你说的对
Someone is staring at you in Personal Growth.
个人成长专架那边有人在盯着你
I know him. You'd like him. He's married.
我认识他.你会喜欢他的,他结婚了
- Who is he? - Harry Burns. He's a political consultant.
- 他是谁? - Harry Burns.他是个政治顾问
He's cute.
他很可爱
- You think he's cute? - How do you know he's married?
- 你认为他可爱? - 你怎么知道他结婚了?
Last time I saw him he was getting married.
上次我见到他时他正准备要结婚
- When was that? - Six years ago.
- 多久之前? - 6年前
So he might not be married any more.
那说不定他已经又是单身了
Also, he's obnoxious.
另外,他很惹人厌
It's like in The Lady Vanishes, when she says "You're the most obnoxious man",...
就像在《贵妇失踪案》里面一样, 她说:"你是最讨厌的人..."
- "The most contemptible". - ..then they fall madly in love.
- "最卑劣的人." - 然后他们疯狂的相爱了
- Also, he never remembers me. - Sally Albright.
- 而且他永远都不会记得我 - Sally Albright.
- Hi, Harry. - I thought it was you.
- 嗨,Harry - 我觉得是你
It is. This is Marie.
是的.这是Marie
Was Marie.
那是Marie
- How are you? - Fine.
- 你怎么样? - 很好
- How's Joe?
- Joe怎么样?
I hear he's fine.
我听说他很好
- You're not with Joe any more? - We just broke up.
- 你和Joe不在一起了吗? - 我们分手了
I'm sorry. That's too bad.
我很遗憾,真是太可惜了
Yeah. Well, you know.
是啊,你知道的
Yeah.
是的
So...
那么...
- What about you? - I'm fine.
- 你怎么样? - 我很好
How's married life?
婚姻生活如何?
I'm getting a divorce.
不太好,我离婚了
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.
我很难过,真的很难过
Yeah, well, what're you gonna do?
是的.但又能怎么样?
What happened with you guys?
你们是怎么了?
When Joe and I started seeing each other we wanted the same thing.
当我和Joe开始交往时我们想法是一样的
We didn't wanna get married because every time anyone we knew got married
我们不想结婚因为所有我们认识的人...
it ruined their relationship. They practically never had sex again.
结婚后都毁了了他们的关系 事实上他们都不再有性生活了.
It's true. That's one of the secrets that no one ever tells you.
这是真的.这是一个大家都不愿意说的秘密
I would sit with my girlfriends who have kids... my one girlfriend with kids, Alice,
我的女友Alice,她有了孩子,我和她交谈时
and she would complain about how she and Gary never did it any more.
她会一直抱怨她和Gary再也没有性生活了
She didn't even complain about it. She said it matter-of-factly.
她甚至不是在抱怨,她只是就事论事的说
She said they were up all night, they were both exhausted,
她说他们整晚不能睡觉,精疲力尽
the kids took every sexual impulse they had out of them.
孩子使他们所有的性冲动都消失了
Joe and I would say "We're so lucky. We have this wonderful relationship."
Joe和我会说:"我们真幸运,有着和谐的关系."
"We can have sex on the kitchen floor and not worry about the kids walking in."
"我们可以在厨房地板上做爱 而不用担心孩子会走进来."
"We can fly off to Rome on a moment's notice."
"也可以心血来潮就飞到罗马去."
Then one day I was taking Alice's girl for the afternoon
一天我带Alice的女儿玩了一个下午...
cos I promised to take her to the circus. We were in the cab playing I-spy.
因为我答应带她去马戏团玩. 我们在出租车里面玩"我偷看"的游戏
"I spy a mailbox", "I spy a lamppost".
"我偷看到邮筒","我偷看到路灯"
And she looked out the window and she saw this man and woman
她从车窗看出去看见了一个男人和一个女人
with these two little kids, and the man had one of the kids on his shoulders.
和他们的两个孩子. 一个孩子坐在爸爸的肩膀上
And she said "I spy a family."
然后她说:"我偷看到一家人."
And I started to cry. You know, I just started crying.
我哭了起来,你知道,就那样哭起来
And I went home and I said "The thing is, Joe,
我回到家对Joe说:"事实上,Joe,"
we never do fly off to Rome on a moment's notice."
"我们从来没有心血来潮的飞去罗马."
And the kitchen floor...?
在厨房地板上...?
Not once. It's this very cold, hard, Mexican ceramic tile.
从没有过.只是又冷又硬的墨西哥瓷砖
Anyway,
总之,
we talked about it for a long time. I said "This is what I want" and he said "I don't".
我们谈了很长时间.我说:"这就是我想要的." 他说:"不是我想要的."
And I said "Well, I guess it's over." And he left.
然后我说:"我想该结束了." 他就走了
And the thing is, I... I feel really fine.
结果是...我真的觉得很好
I am over him. I mean, I really am over him.
我对他没有感觉了,我是说真的没有感觉了
That was it for him. That was the most that he could give.
他就是那样.他能给予的就是那么多
And every time I think about it, I am more and more convinced I did the right thing.
每次我想起这件事,我就更加深信我没做错
Boy, you sound really healthy.
天,你听起来心理真健康
Yeah.
是的
- At least I got the apartment. - That's what everybody says to me.
- 至少我得到了公寓 - 大家也是这样和我说的
But really, what's so hard about finding an apartment? You read the obituary column.
但是为什么说找个公寓那么难? 你可以去读讣告栏
You find out who died, go to the building, and then you tip the doorman.
看看谁死了,去那间公寓,然后贿赂看门人
It'd be easier if they combined obituaries with the real-estate section.
如果他们把讣告和房屋出租 贴在一起那就更简单了
Then you have "Mr Klein died, leaving a wife, two children
然后你就会看到:Klein先生死了, 留下妻子,两个孩子
and a spacious three-bedroom apartment with a wood-burning fireplace."
一个有壁炉的宽敞的3居室公寓
The first time we met I really didn't like you that much.
我们第一次见面时我实在不太喜欢你
- I didn't like you. - Yeah, you did.
- 我也不喜欢你 - 是的,你不喜欢
You were just so uptight then. You're much softer now.
那个时候你太焦躁了,现在和蔼多了
I hate that kind of remark. It sounds like a compliment, but it's an insult.
我讨厌这种评语,听上去像称赞但事实上是侮辱
OK, you're still as hard as nails.
好吧,你还是很难伺候
I didn't wanna sleep with you so you wrote it off as a character flaw,
我只是不想和你上床 你却把这当成性格缺陷
instead of dealing with the possibility it might have something to do with you.
而不想想或许那是因为你的关系
What's the statute of limitations on apologies?
道歉的失效期限会是多长?
- Ten years. - I can just get it in under the wire.
- 10年 - 我刚好过线
Would you like to have dinner with me sometime?
你愿找个时间与我共进晚餐吗?
Are we becoming friends now?
现在我们可以作朋友了吗?
Well...
这个...
Yeah.
是的
Great! A woman friend.
太好了!一个女性朋友
You may be the first attractive woman I've not wanted to sleep with in my entire life.
你会是我有生以来第一个吸引了我 而我不想与之上床的女人
That's wonderful, Harry.
这很好,Harry
- We were born in the same hospital,... - ln 1921 .
- 我们出生在同一家医院 - 在1921年
- ..seven days apart. - ln the same hospital.
- ...只相差7天 - 在同一家医院
- We both grew up one block apart. - We lived in tenements.
- 我们长大的地方只隔一个街区 - 我们都住廉价公寓
- On the Lower East Side. - On Delancey Street.
- 在Lower East Side - 在Delancey街
- I moved to the Bronx when I was ten. - He lived on Fordham Road.
- 我10岁时搬去了Bronx - 他住在Fordham路
- She moved when she was 1 1 . - I lived on 183rd Street.
- 她在11岁的时候搬了家 - 我住在183号大街
- She worked on the 1 5th floor as a nurse. - I worked for a prominent neurologist,...
- 她在15楼当护士 - 我为一个很有名望的神经科医生工作
- I had a practice on the 14th floor. - ..Dr Permelman.
- 我在14楼实习 - Permelman医生
- We never met. - Never met.
- 我们从未遇到过 - 从来没有
- Can you imagine that? - D'you know where we met? An elevator.
- 你能想象吗? - 你知道我们在哪里遇到的吗?电梯里面
- I was visiting family. - ln the Ambassador Hotel.
- 我去拜访亲戚 - 在大使酒店
He was on the third floor, I was on the 1 2th.
他住在3楼,我在12楼
I rode up nine extra floors just to keep talking to her.
我多上了9层楼只为了和她说话
Nine extra floors.
多上了9层
- Hello. - You sleeping?
- 哈罗 - 你睡了吗?
- No, I was watching "Casablanca". - Channel?
- 没有,我在看《卡萨布兰卡》 - 几频道?
- Eleven. - Thank you. Got it.
- 11频道 - 谢谢,找到了
So you'd be happier with Victor Laszlo than with Humphrey Bogart?
你和Victor Laszlo在一起会比和 Humphrey Bogart在一起快乐?
- When did I say that? - When we drove to New York.
- 我什么时候说过? - 在我们去纽约的路上
- I never said that. I'd never say that. - All right, fine. Have it your way.
- 我从来没有说过,没说过 - 好吧,就算没说过
- Have you been sleeping? - Why?
- 你睡得着吗? - 怎么?
Cos I haven't been sleeping. I really miss Helen.
因为我一直睡不着,我真的很想Helen
Maybe I'm coming down with something. I watched "Leave It to Beaver" in Spanish.
我想我有些不对劲 我在看西班牙版的《反斗小宝贝》
"Buenos días, Seòor Cleaver. ?Dónde están Wallace y Theodore?"
(西班牙语)
I'm not well.
我不太好
I went to bed at 7.30. I haven't done that since third grade.
我7:30就睡觉,从我3年级开始的
That's the good thing about depression - you rest.
那倒是对付颓丧的好办法...多休息
- I'm not depressed. - OK. Fine.
- 我并不颓丧 - 好吧
Do you still sleep on the same side ofthe bed?
你还是睡在床的同一边吗?
I did for a while, but now I'm using the whole bed.
有一段时间是,现在我睡整张床
God, that's great. I feel weird when just my leg wanders over.
天啊,太好了.我把腿伸过去时会觉得很奇怪
I miss her.
我很想她
- I don't miss him. I really don't. - Not even a little?
- 我不想他,我真的不想 - 一点也不想?
You know what I miss?
你知道我想念什么吗?
I miss the idea ofhim.
我想念他的鬼点子
Maybe I only miss the idea ofHelen.
也许我只是想Helen的鬼点子
No, I miss the whole Helen.
不,我想念Helen的所有
Last scene.
最后一幕
Goodbye, Rick. God bless you.
再见,Rick,上帝保佑你
lngrid Bergman. She's low maintenance.
英格利 褒曼,她保养的不太好
- Low maintenance? - There are two kinds of women.
- 保养的不好? - 有两种女人
- High maintenance and low maintenance. - And lngrid is low maintenance?
- 保养的好的和保养不好的 - 英格利是保养的不好的?
An LM, definitely.
绝对是
- Which one am I? - The worst kind.
- 我属于那一种? - 最糟糕的那种
You're high maintenance, but you think you're low.
你保养得很好但是以为保养得不好
- I don't see that. - You don't see that?
- 我不觉得 - 不觉得什么?
"Waiter, a house salad, but not the regular dressing."
"侍者,家常沙拉,但是不要普通沙拉酱"
"I'll have balsamic vinegar - on the side."
"我要油和醋--放在旁边."
"Then salmon with mustard sauce, but I want the sauce on the side."
"鲑鱼要加沙司--沙司放在旁边."
- "On the side" is a big thing for you. - I just want it the way I want it.
- "放在旁边"对你来说是件大事 - 我只是想要我喜欢的方式
I know. High maintenance.
我知道,保养的很好
.. 10,000F should pay our expenses.
1万法郎可以付清我们所有费用了
Our expenses?
我们的费用?
Louis, I think this is the beginning of a beautiful friendship.
Louis,我想这是一段美好的友谊的开始
Best last line of a movie ever.
有史以来最好的电影结束台词
I'm definitely coming down with something. Probably a 24-hour tumour.
我肯定是有些不对劲 也许是24小时肿块
- You don't have a tumour. - How do you know?
- 你不会长肿块的 - 你怎么知道?
- If you're so worried, go see a doctor. - No, he'll just tell me it's nothing.
- 如果你很担心,去看医生吧 - 不,医生会告诉我什么也不是的
- Will you be able to sleep? - If not, I'll be OK.
- 你能入睡吗? - 睡不着也没事
- What'll you do? - I'll stay up and moan.
- 你要做什么? - 我会通宵呻吟
Maybe I should practise now.
也许我现在就应该练习下
Good night, Harry.
晚安,Harry
Good night.
晚安
I had my dream again - where I'm making love and Olympic judges are watching?
我又做了同样的梦,我在做爱 奥林匹克裁判在边上看
I'd nailed the compulsories, so this is it: the finals.
我已经击败对手到了最后的决赛
I got a 9.8 from the Canadian, a perfect 10 from the American,
加拿大裁判给了我9.8分 美国裁判给了我10分满分
and my mother, disguised as an East German judge, gave me a 5.6.
我的母亲,伪装成东德裁判给了我5.6分
Must've been the dismount.
肯定是因为下法不好
Basically it's the same one I've had since I was 1 2.
基本上从12岁开始就是一样的梦
- What happens? - No, it's... It's too embarrassing.
- 发生了什么? - 不...这太令人难为情了
- Don't tell me. - OK, there's this guy.
- 那就别告诉我 - 好吧,有一个人
- What's he look like? - I don't know. He's just kinda faceless.
- 他长什么样? - 我不知道.他是个没有面孔的人
A faceless guy. OK. Then what happens?
没有面孔的人,好吧,然后发生了什么?
He rips off my clothes.
他扒下了我的衣服
- Then what happens? - That's it.
- 然后呢? - 就是这样
That's it? A faceless guy rips off your clothes.
就是这样?一个没有面孔的人扒下你的衣服
And that's the sex fantasy you've had since you were 12. Exactly the same?
这就是你从12岁开始的性幻想?一直是这样?
Well, sometimes I vary it a little.
有时会有一些小的变化
- Which part? - What I'm wearing.
- 哪方面的? - 我穿的衣服
- What? - Nothing.
- 什么? - 没什么
I have decided that for today
我决定了今天
we are going to talk like this.
我们要像这样说话
- Like this? - No. To repeat after me.
- 像这样? - 不,重复我的话
- Pepper.
- Pepper.
- Pepper!
- Pepper!
Waiter, there is too much pepper on my paprikash.
Waiter, there is too much pepper on my paprikash.
But I would be proud to partake of your pecan pie.
But I would be proud to partake of your pecan pie.
Oh, no!
哦,不!
- But I would be proud.
- But I would be proud.
- To partake.
- To partake.
- Of your pecan pie.
- Of your pecan pie.
- Pecan pie.
- Pecan pie.
- Pecan pie!
- Pecan pie!
- Would you like to go to the movies? - Would you like to go...
- 你想去看电影吗? - 你想去...
Not to repeat. Please, to answer. Would you like to go to the movies tonight?
不要重复,请回答. 今晚你想和我去看电影吗?
Well, I'd love to, Harry, but I can't.
我很愿意去,Harry,不过我去不了
What do you have? A hot date?
你要干什么?甜蜜的约会?
- Well, yeah. Yeah. - Really?
- 恩,是的. - 真的?
Yeah. I was gonna tell you, but, I don't know, I felt strange about it.
是的.我正想告诉你,但是我觉得有点奇怪
- Why? - Cos we've spent so much time together.
- 为什么? - 因为我们在一起渡过了那么多时间
I think it's great that you have a date.
我认为你能去约会真是太好了
- You do? - Yeah.
- 是吗? - 是的
- Is that what you're gonna wear?
- 你打算就穿成现在这样吗?
Well, I don't know. Why?
这个,我不知道了.为什么?
I think you should wear skirts more. You look really good in skirts.
我认为你应该多穿裙子,你穿裙子很好看
- I do? - Yeah.
- 是吗? - 是的
I think hieroglyphics are really a comic strip about a character named Sphinxy.
我认为象形文字是主角名字 叫斯芬克司的一部连环画
- Harry, you should get out there, too. - I'm not ready.
- Harry,你也应该去约会了 - 我还没准备好
- You should. - I would not be good for anybody now.
- 你应该约会的 - 我现在约会对谁都没有好处
It's time.
是时候了
It was the most uncomfortable night of my life.
那是我有生以来最不舒服的一夜
See, no, it has to go this way.
不对,这个要往那边
The first date back is always the toughest, Harry.
第一次约会回来总是最糟的一次,Harry
You only had one date.
你才约会了一次
- How do you know it won't get worse? - How much worse can it get
- 你怎么知道不会变得更糟糕? - 还能变得多糟糕?
than finishing dinner, having him pull a hair out of my head and floss with it?
比吃完饭拉下我的头发乱扔更糟?
We're talking dream date compared to my horror.
你在用梦到的约会和我悲惨的遭遇对比
It started out fine. She's a very nice person.
一开始还不错,她是个好人
And we're talking in this Ethiopian restaurant she wanted to go to.
我们开始谈论她想去的埃塞俄比亚餐厅
I was making jokes, like "I didn't know they had food in Ethiopia."
我开玩笑,比如"我不知道埃塞俄比亚有没有吃的."
"This'll be a quick meal. I'll order two empty plates and we can leave."
"肯定会是很快的一餐,我会点两个空盘子 然后我们就可以走了."
Yeah! Nothing from her, not even a smile.
结果毫无反映,连个微笑都没有
I downshift into small talk and ask where she went to school.
我开始改变话题问她是在哪儿上的学
She says Michigan State. And this reminds me of Helen.
她说是密歇根州大学.这让我想起Helen
All of a sudden I'm in the middle of an anxiety attack -
突然间我被强烈的焦虑包围...
my heart's beatin' fast and I start sweatin' like a pig.
心跳加速,汗流不止
- Helen went to Michigan State? - No, Northwestern.
- Helen也是密歇根州大学的? - 不,西北大学
But they're both Big Ten schools.
但是它们都是10大名校
I got so upset I had to leave the restaurant.
我开始沮丧,必须离开餐厅
Harry, I think this takes a long time.
Harry,我想这需要很长时间
It might be months before we're able to enjoy going out with someone new.
也许需要数月才能和别人愉快的约会
Yeah.
是的
Maybe longer before we're able to go to bed with someone new.
也许要更长的时间才能和别人上床
I went to bed with her.
我和她上床了
- You went to bed with her?! - Sure.
- 你和她上床了? - 没错
- I don't understand this relationship. - What d'ya mean?
- 我不明白你们这算什么关系 - 什么意思?
- Enjoy being with her? - Yeah.
- 喜欢和她在一起 - 是的
- You find her attractive?
- 你觉得她很迷人?
- And you're not sleeping with her? - No.
- 你却没有和她上床 - 没有
You're afraid to let yourself be happy.
你害怕让自己快乐
Why can't you gimme credit for this? This is a big thing for me.
为什么你不能给我点信心?这对我很重要
I never had a relationship with a woman that didn't involve sex. I'm growing.
我从没和不涉及性关系的女人交往过,我在成长
- Are you finished? - I got a stack o' quarters. I was here first.
- 你打完了吗? - 我投了很多铜板,是我先来的
- Were not. - Was too.
- 不是 - 是
- Big jerk. - Little creep.
- 大混蛋 - 小讨厌
- Where was I? - You were growing.
- 说到哪了? - 你在成长
Yeah.
对
It's very freeing. I can say anything to her.
感觉很自由,我可以和她说任何事情
Are you saying you can say things to her you can't say to me?
你是说可以和她说都不能和我说的事?
No, it's just a different perspective. I get the woman's point of view on things.
不,是完全不一样的.我可以知道女性怎么看
She tells me about the men she sees, and I talk to her about the women I see.
她和我讨论她约会的男人 我和她讨论我约会的女人
- You tell her about other women? - Yeah.
- 你和她谈论其他女人? - 是的
Like the other night, I made love to this woman and it was incredible.
比如有一晚,我和一个女人做爱,难以置信
I took her to a place that wasn't human. She actually meowed.
我让她变成了异类,她开始喵喵叫
- You made a woman meow? - Yeah, and I can say these things to her.
- 你让一个女人喵喵叫? - 是的,我把这件事告诉了她
And the great thing is, I don't have to lie because I don't wanna get her into bed.
最棒的是,我不需要说谎因为我不想和她上床
- I can just be myself. - You made a woman meow?
- 我可以做我自己 - 你使一个女人喵喵叫?
What do you do with these women? Just get up and leave?
你后来怎么对她的?只是起身离开吗?
- Sure. - Explain how you do it. What do you say?
- 没错 - 解释下你怎么做到的,你说了什么?
I say I have an early meeting, early squash game.
我说我早晨要开会,还要去打壁球
- You don't play squash. - They don't know that. They just met me.
- 你从不打壁球 - 她们又不知道,她们刚认识我
- That's disgusting. - I know. I feel terrible.
- 这样很讨厌 - 我知道,我感觉很不好
I'm so glad I never got involved with you.
我真高兴我不需要和你有瓜葛
I just would've been some woman you had to get outta bed and leave at 3am
我不会成为那个和你上床 而你会在凌晨3点离去的女人
and go clean your andirons. You don't even have a fireplace.
我也不需要清洗你的铁制柴架,你都没有壁炉
- Not that I would know this. - Why are you upset? This isn't about you.
- 现在我都知道了 - 你为什么不高兴?又不是和你有关的
Yes, it is! You are a human affront to all women, and I am a woman.
是的,有关系.你冒犯了所有的女人 而我是个女人
Hey, I don't hear anyone complaining.
我从来没有听到过抱怨
Of course not. You're out the door too fast.
当然没有,你离开得太快了
- I think they have an OK time. - How do you know?
- 我认为她们都觉得还不错 - 你怎么知道?
What d'ya mean how do I know? I know.
我怎么知道?我就是知道
- Because they... - Yes, because they...
- 因为她们... - 是的,因为她们...
- How do you know that they're really... - What're you saying? They fake orgasm?
- 你怎么知道那是真的... - 你什么意思? 她们假装达到高潮?
- It's possible. - Get outta here!
- 有可能 - 怎么可能?
Why? Most women at one time or another have faked it.
为什么不可能?大多数女人都假装过一两次
- They haven't faked it with me. - How do you know?
- 她们没有欺骗我 - 你怎么知道?
Because I know.
因为我知道
Right. That's right.
好吧,没错
I forgot. You're a man.
我忘记了,你是个男人
- What is that supposed to mean? - Nothing.
- 这是什么意思? - 没什么
All men are sure it never happened to them and most women have done it,
男人都觉得这种事不会发生在他身上 而大多数女人却都做过
so you do the math.
你自己想想吧
You don't think I could tell the difference?
你认为我分辨不出来真假吗?
- No. - Get outta here.
- 分不出 - 不可能
Are you OK?
你没事吧?
Oh, God.
Oh,God
Oh, yeah, right there.
Oh, yeah, right there
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Yes! Yes!
Yes! Yes!
Yes!
Yes!
Oh, yes! Yes! Yes!
Oh, yes! Yes! Yes!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Yes! Yes! Yes!
Oh, God.
Oh, God!
I'll have what she's having.
我要她点的那些
~ "But you can do thejob when you're in town, brother"
<"But you can do the job when you're in town, brother">
- I like you with no beard. I see your face. - It is my face!
- 我喜欢你把胡子刮掉.可以看到你的脸 - 这就是我的脸
Whoa! Dipping you.
放下你了
- Thank you for taking me out tonight. - Don't be silly.
- 谢谢你今晚带我出来 - 别傻了
The next New Year's Eve, if neither of us is with anybody, you got a date.
明年的新年夜,如果我们都没有 和别人交往,你就有了个男伴
Deal.
成交
See? Now we can dance cheek to cheek.
看,我们可以脸贴脸的跳舞了
Hey, everybody! Ten seconds to New Year!
大家注意!还有10秒钟到新年!
- Ten,... - Wanna get some air?
- 10... - 想出去透透气吗?
- Yeah. - ..seven, six, five, four,
- 好的 - ...7,6,5,4
three, two, one!
3,2,1!
Happy New Year!
新年快乐!
- Happy New Year.
- 新年快乐!
He was a head counsellor at boys' camp, I was a head counsellor at girls' camp,
他是男生营的辅导员 我是女生营的辅导员
and they had a social one night, and he walked across the room.
一天晚上营之间有活动,他穿过房间走过来
I thought he was coming to talk to my friend Maxine,
我以为他是想和我朋友Maxine交谈
cos people were always crossing rooms to talk to Maxine.
因为总是有人会来和Maxine交谈
But he was coming to talk to me, and he said
可是他是来找我的,他说
"I'm Ben Small of the Coney lsland Smalls."
我是Coney岛Smalls家族的Ben Small
At that moment I knew. I knew the way you know about a good melon.
那一刻我就明白了.就想你明白了怎么挑瓜一样
You sent flowers to yourself.
你给自己送了花
$60 I spent on this big arrangement of flowers, and I wrote a card
我花了60美圆买那个大插花,我还写了张卡片
that I planned to leave on the table where Arthur would just happen to see it.
我打算放到桌子上让Arthur碰巧看到
What did the card say?
卡上面写了什么?
"Please say yes. Love Jonathan."
"答应我吧.爱你的Jonathan."
- Did it work? - He never even came over.
- 有用吗? - 他甚至都没来过
He forgot a charity thing his wife is chairman of. He's never gonna leave her!
他忘记了去她太太当主席的机构募捐 他不可能离开她了
- Of course he isn't. - You're right. I know you're right.
- 他当然不会了 - 你说得对,我知道你说得对
- Where is this place? - Somewhere on the next block.
- 是在什么地方? - 下个街区的一个地方
I can't believe I'm doing this.
我不敢相信自己在做什么
Harry is one of my best friends and you are one of my best friends.
Harry是我最好的朋友,你也是我最好的朋友
And if you two hit it off, we could still be friends, instead of drifting apart
如果你们两个擦出了火花, 我们还可以是朋友,不用分开
like you do when you date someone who doesn't know your friends.
就像你在和不认识你朋友的人约会后那样
You and I haven't drifted apart since I started seeing Arthur.
我和Arthur交往也没有让你我关系疏远啊
If Arthur ever left his wife and I actually met him,
如果Arthur离开了他妻子 而我又真正遇见喜欢的人
I am sure that you and I would drift apart.
我确定你和我会因此疏远的
He's never gonna leave her.
他永远不会离开她的
Of course he isn't.
他当然不会了
You're right. I know you're right.
你是对的,我知道你是对的
- I dunno about this. - It's just a dinner.
- 这事我说不好 - 只是吃顿饭
I've finally gotten to a place where I'm comfortable with just me and my work.
我终于找到了我生活中的支点 我只对我自己和我的工作感到满意
- If she's so great why don't you date her? - I told you. We're just friends.
- 如果她真的那么好为什么你不约她? - 我告诉你了,我们只是朋友
- So she's not attractive? - No, she is attractive.
- 那么,她不迷人吗? - 不,她很迷人
- You said she had a good personality. - She has a good personality.
- 你说她人品很好 - 她的人品是很好
What?
怎么了?
When someone's not attractive, they're described as having a good personality.
当一个人不迷人的时候, 人们总是用人品好来形容她
If you'd asked about looks and I'd said "She has a good personality",
如果你问我长相而我说:"她人品很好."
she's not attractive.
那是说她不迷人
But because I mentioned she has a good personality, she can be either.
但是因为我提到了她人品很好, 她可能二者都具备
Attractive with a good personality, or not attractive with a good personality.
人品又好又迷人还是人品很好不迷人
- So which one is she? - Attractive.
- 她属于那一种? - 很迷人
But not beautiful, right?
但是不漂亮,对吧?
It's like, whenever I read Jimmy Breslin, it's as if he's leaving a wake-up call
这就像不管什么时候我读到Jimmy Breslin, 他好像都是在安排唤醒电话
- for the City of New York. - What d'you mean by a "wake-up call"?
- 为纽约准备的 - 你说的"唤醒电话"是什么意思?
He's saying that we've got people in the city who are on welfare...
他说我们的城市里面获得福利的人...
Would I have seen any of your windows?
我看过你设计的展示窗吗?
A couple of weeks ago I did a thing with hostages.
几周前我刚刚做了个人质主题的
- The people in blindfolds. - Yeah.
- 戴着眼罩的人? - 是的
I thought it was like late '80s.
我觉得那样有80年代的感觉
That's interesting.
很有意思
Let's just say I'm not a big fan of Jimmy Breslin.
只能说我不太热衷Jimmy Breslin
Well, he's the reason I became a writer, but that's not important.
他是我成为作家的原因,但那不重要
Harry, you and Marie are both from New Jersey.
Harry,你和Marie都是新泽西人
- Really? - Where?
- 是吗? - 什么地方?
- South Orange. - Haddonfield.
- South Orange. - Haddonfield.
- So, what are we gonna order? - I'm gonna start with the grilled radicchio.
- 好吧,我们点些什么呢? - 我想先来点烤菊苣
Jess, Sally is a great orderer. Not only does she pick the best,
Jess,Sally是个点菜专家.不仅能点出最好的,
but she orders it in a way even the chef didn't know how good it could be.
而且她可以用自己的方法搭配出 主厨都无法相信的美味
- Restaurants have become too important. - I agree.
- 餐厅变得过于重要了 - 我同意
"Restaurants are to people in the '80s what theatre was to people in the '60s."
"80年代餐厅的重要性就像60年代电影院一样."
I read that in a magazine.
我在杂志上看到的
I wrote that.
那是我写的
- Get outta here. - No, I did! I wrote that.
- 别逗了 - 没有,是真的.是我写的
I've never quoted anything from a magazine. That's amazing.
我从来没有从杂志引用过话,真不可思议
Don't you think that's amazing? And you wrote it?
你们不认为这很不可思议吗?是你写的?
I also wrote "Pesto is the quiche of the '80s."
我还写了"香蒜沙司是80年代的乳蛋饼."
- Get over yourself! - I did!
- 少来了! - 是真的!
- Where did I read that? - New York Magazine.
- 我是从哪里看到的? - 《纽约杂志》
Sally writes for New York Magazine.
Sally也为《纽约杂志》写东西
You know, that piece had a real impact on me. I don't know much about writing...
你知道吗,那篇文章对我影响很大. 我对写作了解不多...
It spoke to you, and that pleases me.
不得不说这让我很高兴
I mean, you have to admire people who can be that articulate.
我是说你必须要赞美那些能把问题阐述清楚的人
Nobody has ever quoted me back to me before.
以前从来没有人在背地里引用过我的话
I've been looking for a red suede pump.
我一直在找一双红色的小山羊皮鞋
What do you think of Jess?
你认为Jess怎么样?
- Well... - Do you think you could go out with him?
- 恩... - 你认为你想和他约会吗?
- I don't know... - Cos I feel really comfortable with him.
- 我不知道... - 因为我觉得和他在一起很愉快
- You wanna go out with Jess. - If it would be all right with you.
- 你想和Jess约会 - 如果你认为这样可以的话
Sure. Sure. I'm just worried about Harry.
好的,好的,我只是为Harry担心
He's sensitive, he's going through a rough period, and I don't want you to reject him.
他很敏感,正在渡过失恋期,我不想你拒绝他
I wouldn't. I totally understand.
我不会的,我完全能够理解
If you don't think you're gonna call Marie, do you mind if I call her?
如果你不打算约Marie,你介意我约她吗?
- No, no. - Good. Good.
- 不,不介意 - 好,很好
But for tonight you shouldn't. I mean, Sally's very vulnerable right now.
但是不要在今晚.我是说,Sally现在很脆弱
You can call Marie, but wait a week or so. Don't make any moves tonight.
你可以约Marie,但是先等几周.不要在今晚
Fine. No problem. I wasn't even thinking about tonight.
好的,没问题.我从没想过在今晚
Well, I don't feel like walking any more. I think I'll get a cab.
我不太想走路了,我想搭计程车了
- I'll go with you. - Great! Taxi!
- 我和你一起走 - 太棒了!计程车!
A man came to me and said "I found nice girl for you."
有人告诉我说:"我给你找了个好女孩."
"She lives in the next village
"她住在隔壁村子里..."
and she is ready for marriage."
"她已经准备好要结婚了."
We were not supposed to meet until the wedding,
在婚礼前我们本不应该见面的
but I wanted to make sure.
但是我想确定一下
So I sneak into her village, hid behind a tree,
所以我偷偷溜到她们村子里,藏在一棵树后面
watch her washing the clothes.
看她在那洗衣服
I think if I don't like the way she looks, I don't marry her.
我想要是我不喜欢她的相貌我就不娶她
But she looked very nice to me.
但是我觉得她看上去很不错
So I said "OK" to the man.
所以我和那个人说同意结婚
We get married.
我们结婚了
We married for 55 years.
我们结婚已经55年了
FOUR MONTHS LATER
(4个月后)
- I have to get this. - Harry, we're here for Jess and Marie.
- 我一定要买这个 - Harry,我们是来给Jess和Marie买礼物的
- We'll find something. Great stuff. - Should have gone to the plant store.
- 我们会找到些很棒的东西 - 我们应该去卖植物的商店
- Here. Perfect for them. - What's that?
- 这个,很适合他们 - 这是什么?
Battery-operated pith helmet, with fan.
电池驱动的带风扇的头盔
- Why is this necessary in life? - I don't know.
- 为什么这是生活必需品? - 我不知道
Look at this. Also makes great fries.
看这个,还可以做炸薯条
Good. Call off the dogs. The hunt is over.
很好,把狗叫回来,狩猎结束了
Sally, this is the greatest.
Sally,这是最棒的
Sally, please report to me.
Sally,请向我报告
Look. This is the greatest. You're gonna love this.
看啊,这个是最棒的,你会喜欢的
This is a singing machine. Look, you sing the lead and this has the backup.
这是个伴唱机.看啊,你开始唱它就给你伴奏
- This is from Oklahoma! - "Surrey with the Fringe on Top".
- 这是从俄克拉荷马州来的 - "Surrey with the Fringe on Top".
Yes, perfect.
是的,很棒
with the fringe on top
<When I take you out in my surrey with the fringe on top>
Now you!
该你了
~ When I drive those high-steppin' strutters
<When I drive those high-steppin' strutters>
~ Nosey pokes'll peek through the shutters
<Nosey pokes'll peek through the shutters>
~ The wheels are yellow, the upholstery's brown
<The wheels are yellow, the upholstery's brown>
What?
怎么了?
It's my voice, isn't it? You hate my voice.
因为我的声音,对吧?我讨厌我的声音
- I know, it's terrible. Joe hated it... - It's Helen.
- 我知道那不好听.Joe不喜欢... - 那是Helen
Helen?
Helen?
She's coming right towards me.
她正向我走过来
- How are you, Harry? - Fine. I'm fine.
- 你好吗,Harry? - 很好,我很好
This is Ira Stone. Harry Burns.
这是Ira Stone. Harry Burns.
Harry.
Harry.
I'm sorry. This is Sally Albright. Helen Hillson
抱歉,这是Sally Albright.Helen Hillson
and Ira.
和Ira
Sally.
Sally.
- Nice to meet you. - Hi.
- 很高兴见到你 - 嗨
Well...
那么...
- See you. - Yeah. Bye.
- 再见 - 好的,拜拜
Nice to meet you, Ira.
很高兴见到你,Ira
You OK?
你没事吧?
Yeah, I'm perfect.
是的,我很好
She looked weird, didn't she? She looked really weird.
她看上去很奇怪,是不是. 她看上去实在很奇怪
- I've never seen her before. - Trust me. Her legs looked heavy.
- 我从来没有见过她 - 相信我,她的腿看上去很粗
- Must be retaining water. - Harry!
- 肯定是浮肿了 - Harry!
Believe me, the woman saved everything.
相信我,这个女人什么都留着
Sure you're OK?
你肯定没事吗?
I'm fine. Look, it had to happen at some point.
我很好.看啊,这总是会发生的
In a city of eight million, you're bound to run into your ex-wife. So it happened.
在一个有800万人口的城市中,你和你的前妻相遇 就是这样发生了
And now I'm fine.
现在我很好
I like it. It works. It says "home" to me.
我喜欢这个,这很好.对我来说有家的感觉
All right. All right. We'll let Harry and Sally be the judge.
好吧,好吧.我们让Harry和Sally评判
What do you think?
你们认为怎么样?
- It's nice. - Case closed.
- 很好 - 讨论结束了
Of course he likes it - he's a guy.
当然他会喜欢,他是个男人
Sally?
Sally?
What's so awful about it?
这有什么难看的?
It's so awful, there's no way to begin to explain what's so awful about it.
这很难看,都无从所起它有多难看
Honey, I don't object to your things.
亲爱的,我没有说过你的东西
If we had room, you could put your things in it, like your bar stools...
如果我们有房间,你可以放你的东西 就像你的高脚椅...
Honey, wait, wait. Honey, wait. You don't like my bar stools?
亲爱的,等下,亲爱的,你不喜欢我的高脚椅?
Harry, come on, someone has to be on my side.
Harry,来吧,总得有人站到我的一边
I'm on your side. I just want you to have good taste.
我站在你的那边.我只是希望你能有品味
I have good taste!
我很有品味!
Everybody thinks they have good taste, but they couldn't all have good taste.
人人都以为自己很有品味, 但是不可能所有人都有品味
You know, it's funny. We started out like this, Helen and I.
你知道吗,很好笑.我和Helen就是这样开始的
We hung things, we picked out tiles together. Then you know what happens?
我们装饰悬挂物,我们一起挑瓷砖, 然后你知道发生什么了吗?
Six years later you're singing "Surrey with the Fringe on Top" in front of lra!
6年以后你在Ira面前唱着 "Surrey with the Fringe on Top"
- Do we have to talk about this right now? - Yes. Right now is the perfect time,
- 我们现在必须要说这个吗? - 是的,现在就是最应该说的时候
because I want our friends to benefit from the wisdom of my experience.
因为我想我的朋友能从我的经验里面受益
Right now everything is great. Everyone is happy and in love, and that's wonderful.
现在什么都很好.人人都快乐着相爱着,这很好
But sooner or later, you'll be screaming at each other about who'll get this dish.
但是早晚你会互相争吵着谁该得到这个盘子
This $8 dish will cost $1 ,000 in calls to the legal firm of "That's mine, this is yours".
这个8美圆的盘子会花掉1000美圆的电话费 来通过法律断定"这是我的,这是你的."
- Harry! - Please.
- Harry! - 别这样
Jess, Marie, do me a favour for your own good.
Jess,Marie,为了你们自己好帮我个忙
Put your name in your books right now before you don't know whose is whose,
现在就把书上都写上你们的名字, 不要等到不知道谁的是谁的
because some day you'll go 1 5 rounds over who's gonna get this coffee table.
因为有天你们会大战15回合决定这个咖啡桌归谁
This stupid, wagon-wheel, Roy-Rogers, garage-sale coffee table!
这个愚蠢的带马车轮的Roy-Rogers 清仓拍卖的咖啡桌
- I thought you liked it. - I was being nice!
- 我以为你喜欢它 - 我在客气
He just bumped into Helen.
他刚刚遇到了Helen
I want you to know
我想让你知道
that I will never want that wagon-wheel coffee table.
我永远不会要那个马车轮咖啡桌的
I know, I know, I shouldn't have done it.
我知道,我知道,我不应该那样
Harry, you have to try to find a way of not expressing every feeling you have,
Harry,你必须想个办法不要把你 不好的感觉都表达出来...
every moment that you have them.
在任何你感觉不好的时候
- Oh, really? - Yes.
- 是吗? - 是的
There are times and places for things.
发火要分时间和地点
Well, the next time you're giving a lecture on social graces, tell me cos I'll sign up.
那好,下次你有社交礼仪演讲的时候 告诉我我要参加
Hey! You don't have to take your anger out on me.
嘿!你没必要向我发火
I'm entitled to throw anger your way.
我有资格向你发火
Especially when I'm being told how to live my life by Miss Hospital Corners!
特别是当我被告知如何和我的 "医院拐角小姐"生活的时候
- What's that supposed to mean? - Nothing bothers you!
- 那是什么意思? - 任何事情都不会困扰你
- You never get upset about anything! - Don't be ridiculous!
- 你从来不因为任何事情生气吗 - 别像个傻瓜
What?
什么?
You never get upset about Joe. I never see it back up on you. How is it possible?
你从来不生Joe的气.我从来没有看到 这怎么可能?
- Don't you experience feelings of loss? - I don't have to take this crap.
- 你没有感到失落吗? - 我不用听你的废话
- If you're over Joe, why not see people? - I see people!
- 如果你对Joe没感觉了,为什么不交往其他人? - 我在交往!
See people! Have you slept with one person since Joe?
交往!你和Joe分手后和其他人上过床吗?
What the hell does that have to do with anything?
这有什么关系吗?
That will prove I'm over Joe because I fuck somebody?!
我和别人做爱就能证明我对Joe没感觉了?
You have to move back to New Jersey cos you've slept with everyone in New York.
你必须要回新泽西 因为你和纽约的每个人上过床了
I don't see that turning Helen into a faint memory for you.
我没看到那样能让你忘掉Helen
Besides, I will make love when it is making love.
另外,只有有爱的时候我才做爱
Not the way you do it, like you're out for revenge or something.
不像你那样,好像要发泄一样
Are you finished now?
你说完了吗?
Yes.
是的
Can I say something?
我可以说点什么吗?
I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
对不起,对不起
Don't say a word!
一个字都别说
It's a monkey, a monkey. Monkey see, monkey do.
是猴子,一只猴子,猴子在看,猴子在干什么
- It's an ape. Going ape. - It's a baby!
- 是猿猴,变成猿猴 - 是个宝宝
- Planet ofthe Apes! - She said baby! Try Planet ofthe Dopes.
- 人猿星球! - 她说是宝宝,试试笨蛋星球
- It doesn't look like a baby. - Big mouth. Jagger as a baby.
- 看上去不像个宝宝 - 大嘴,锯齿宝宝...
- Baby ape! - Stop with the apes.
- 人猿宝宝 - 别说人猿了
- Baby's breath. - Rosemary's Baby's mouth?
- 宝宝在呼吸 - Rosemary的宝宝嘴?
- "Won't You Come Home, Bill Baby?" - Kiss the baby!
- "你会回来吗,Bill宝宝?" - 亲吻宝宝
- "Melancholy Baby's Mouth"! - Baby fish... Baby-fish mouth!
- 忧郁的宝宝嘴 - 宝宝鱼..宝宝鱼嘴
- 1 5 seconds. - A big mouth.
- 15秒 - 一张大嘴
- Baby boom! - Baby...
- 宝宝爆炸 - 宝宝...
Draw something resembling anything!
画什么不像什么
- Crying baby. Kiss the baby. - Baby spitting up... Exorcist Baby!
- 哭泣的宝宝，亲吻宝宝 - 宝宝吐口水...驱魔宝宝!
- "Yes Sir, That's My Baby". - "No sir, don't mean maybe."
- 是的,先生,那是我的宝宝 - 不,先生,或许不是
- That's it. Time's up. - Baby talk.
- 好了,时间到 - 宝宝说话
Baby talk? What's that? That's not a saying.
宝宝说话?那算什么?那不是谚语
But "baby-fish mouth" is sweeping the nation! I hear them talking!
但是"宝宝鱼嘴"在全国流行,我经常听得到
Final score. Our team: 1 10.
最后比分,我们队:110分
You guys: 60.
你们:60分
- Ouch. Fix! Definitely a fix. - Pathetic.
- 哦,扯平了,终于扯平了 - 可怜啊
- I can't draw. - That's a baby, and it's clearly talking.
- 我不会画画 - 那是个宝宝,很明显在说话
You're wonderful.
你很棒
- Who wants coffee? - I do, and I love you.
- 谁要咖啡? - 我要,我爱你
- D'you have tea? - lndustrial strength.
- 你要茶吗? - 浓茶
- I'll help you. Decaf? - Yeah.
- 我去帮你,无咖啡因的? - 是的
- Three. - Yes, please.
- 3杯 - 是的,谢谢
- Where's the bathroom? - Through that door, down the hall.
- 洗手间在哪里? - 穿过那个门在走廊尽头
Never looked like a baby to me.
怎么看都不像是个宝宝
- Which part? - All of it.
- 哪部分? - 整个
- You were gonna show me a book cover. - Yeah, it's in the den.
- 你要给我看一本书的封面 - 是的,在小书房
Julian, help yourself. Have some more wine, whatever, OK?
Julian,请随便,喝点酒之类的,好吗?
I like saying den. Got a nice ring to it.
我喜欢说小书房,听起来不错
Emily's a little young for Harry, don't you think?
Emily对Harry来说年轻了点,你不这样认为吗?
Well, she's young, but look what she's done.
是的,她是年轻,不过看看她做了什么
What has she done? She makes desserts.
她做了什么?她做了甜点
- Does Julian seem a little stuffy to you? - He's a good guy. You should talk to him.
- 你觉得Julian有点乏味吗? - 他不错,你应该和他聊聊
He's too tall to talk to.
他太高了,不方便聊天
She makes 3,500 chocolate-mousse pies a week.
她一周做了3500块巧克力慕斯派
Emily is "Aunt Emily"?
Emily是"Emily姑妈"?
He took us to a Met game last week. It was great.
上周他带我们去看了棒球赛,很精彩
- You all went to a Met game together? - Yeah, but it was a last-minute thing.
- 你们一起去看了棒球比赛? - 是的,不过那时临时决定的
But Sally hates baseball.
可是Sally不喜欢棒球
Harry doesn't even like sweets.
Harry甚至不喜欢甜食
Julian is great.
Julian很不错
I know. He's a grown-up.
我知道,他想法很成熟
- Emily is terrific. - Yeah. But when I asked where she was
- Emily很不错 - 是的.但是当我问她...
when Kennedy was shot, she said "Ted Kennedy was shot?"
肯尼迪遇刺时她在哪,她说"特德肯尼迪遇刺了?"
- Hello? - Are you alone?
- 哈罗? - 你是一个人吗?
Yeah. I was just finishing a book.
是的,我正在看书
- Could you come over? - What's the matter?
- 你能过来吗? - 出什么事了?
- He's getting married. - Who?
- 他要结婚了 - 谁?
Joe!
Joe!
I'll be right there.
我马上到
- Hi. - Are you all right?
- 嗨 - 你还好吗?
Come on in.
进来
- I'm sorry to call you so late. - It's all right.
- 很抱歉这么晚给你打电话 - 没关系
- I need a Kleenex! - OK.
- 我需要面巾纸 - 好的
OK. OK.
好的
He just called me up, "Wanted to see how you were",
他刚刚打来电话,"你近况如何?"
"Fine. How are you?" "Fine."
"很好,你怎么样?""很好."
His secretary's on vacation, everything's all backed up.
他的秘书在度假,事情都推迟了
He's got a big case in Newark, blah, blah, blah.
他在纽约接了个大案子,等等等
And I'm sitting on the phone thinking "I am over him, I really am over him,
我坐在那接着电话想: "我对他没感觉了,一点没感觉了."
I can't believe I was ever remotely interested in any of this."
"我无法想象竟然曾经会那样."
And then he said "I have some news."
然后他说:"我有个新消息"
She works in his office. She's a paralegal. Her name is Kimberly.
她在他的事务所工作,她是律师助手 她的名字叫Kimberly
He just met her!
他才认识她
She's supposed to be his transitional person, not "the one"!
她应该是那个过渡时期的人的人才对 不应该是最后结婚那个
All this time, I've been saying that he didn't wanna get married.
一直以来,我一直在说他不想结婚
But the truth is,
但是事实是
he didn't wanna marry me.
他不想和我结婚
He didn't love me.
他不爱我
If you could take him back right now, would you?
如果你现在能让他回心转意,你想吗?
No!
不!
But why didn't he wanna marry me?
但是为什么他不想娶我?
- What's the matter with me? - Nothing.
- 我有什么问题吗? - 没有
- I'm difficult. - You're challenging.
- 我很难相处 - 你很吸引人
- I'm too structured. I'm closed off. - But in a good way.
- 我太固执,我太封闭 - 但是都是在好的方面
No, no, no. I drove him away.
不,不,不,是我把他赶跑的
And I'm gonna be 40!
而我快要40岁了!
When?
什么时候?
- Some day. - ln eight years.
- 某一天 - 8年以后
But it's there! It's just sitting there like this big dead end.
但是总会这样的,就像个死胡同在那等着
And it's not the same for men. Charlie Chaplin had babies when he was 73.
而且对男人来说这不一样. 查理卓别林在73岁还生了孩子
Yeah, but he was too old to pick 'em up.
是的,不过他太老了没法养大了
Come here. Come here.
过来,过来
It's gonna be OK.
一切都会好的
It's gonna be fine, you'll see.
会好起来的,等着看吧
Go ahead. It's not one of my favourites anyway.
继续,反正不是我最喜欢的一件
It's gonna be OK. Hm?
会好起来的
Hm? OK?
好了
- I'll make some tea. - Harry, could you hold me a little longer?
- 我去给泡杯茶 - Harry,你能再多抱我一会吗?
Oh, sure.
当然了
OK? Hm?
好了?
Are you comfortable?
感觉舒服吗?
Sure.
当然
- D'you want something to drink? - No, I'm OK.
- 想要些什么喝的吗? - 不用了,我很好
I'm going to get up for some water, so it's really no trouble.
我要起来去拿些水,所以这不麻烦
OK. Water.
好的,水
You have all your video tapes alphabetised and on index cards.
你把你的录像带都按字母顺序做了索引卡
Thank you.
谢谢
- D'you wanna watch something? - No. Not unless you do.
- 你想看些什么吗? - 不,除非你想
No. That's OK.
不,不想看
- D'you wanna go to sleep? - OK.
- 你想睡觉吗? - 好的
Where are you going?
你去哪?
I gotta go.
我该走了
Gotta go home, change my clothes and go to work. And so do you.
回家,换衣服然后去工作.你也应该这样
But after work I'd like to take you out to dinner, if you're free. You free?
不过下班后我想带你去吃晚餐 如果你有空的话,你有空吗?
- Yes. - Fine. I'll call you later.
- 是的 - 好的,晚些给你打电话
- Fine.
- 好的
- Yours! - Hello.
- 你的 - 哈罗
- Sorry to call so early. - Are you all right?
- 真抱歉这么早打电话 - 你没事吧?
No one I know would call at this hour.
我知道不会有别人这个时候打电话的
- No one I know would call. - It's awful.
- 谁也不会打 - 这很糟糕
- I need to talk. - What happened?
- 我需要谈谈 - 出什么事了?
- Harry came over. - I went to Sally's.
- Harry来我家了 - 我去了Sally家
- I was upset Joe was marrying. - One thing led to another.
- 我因为Joe结婚的事很沮丧 - 事情一件接一件发生
- Before I knew it we were kissing. Then... - ..we did it.
- 我知道之前我们接吻了,然后... - ...我们做了那事
They did it!
他们做爱了!
- That's great! - We prayed for it.
- 这很好 - 我们一直期望这样
- You shoulda done it before. - We said you should do it.
- 你们早该这样了 - 我们说你们应该这样
- You belong together. - You killed two birds with one stone.
- 你们属于彼此 - 这就像一石二鸟
- Two wrongs make a right. - How was it?
- 负负得正 - 感觉如何?
- During part was good,... - Good,...
- 做的时候感觉很不错... - 很好...
- ..then I felt suffocated. - ..then it wasn't.
- ...接着我有窒息的感觉 - ...接着就不那么好了
- Sorry. - The worst.
- 我很难过 - 更糟的
- I had to go. - He left.
- 我必须走了 - 他走了
- I feel bad. - I'm embarrassed.
- 我感觉很糟 - 我觉得很尴尬
I don't blame you.
我不会责怪你 那太糟糕了
- I feel ill. - I'm catching a cold.
- 我觉得像病了 - 我感冒了
Look, it didn't work out.
看啊,这样不行
Never sleep with anyone when you find out your ex is marrying.
当你发现你的前男友结婚时 不要和任何人上床
- Who's talking? - Is that Jess?
- 谁在说话? - 是Jess吗?
- It's Jane Fonda on the VCR. - It's Bryant Gumbel.
- 是录像带里面的Jane Fonda - 是Bryant Gumbel
Wanna have breakfast?
想吃早餐吗?
- No, I'm not up to it. - I feel too awful.
- 不,我不想吃 - 我感觉很糟
- Good. - I mean, it's so early.
- 好的 - 我的意思是太早了
- But call me later. - I'll call you later.
- 过会打给我 - 我晚些时候打给你
- OK. Bye. - Bye.
- 好的,拜拜 - 拜拜
- God! - I know.
- 天啊! - 我知道
Tell me I'll never have to be out there again.
告诉我永远不用再经历这种事了
You will never have to be out there again.
你永远不用再经历这种事了
I'll just say we made a mistake.
我就说我们犯了个错误
Sally, it was a mistake.
Sally,那是个错误
I just hope I get to say it first.
我只希望我能先说出来
I hope she says it before I do.
我希望她比我先说出来
- It was a mistake. - I am so relieved that you think so, too.
- 这是个错误 - 知道你也这样想我就放心了
I'm not saying last night wasn't great.
我不是说昨天晚上不好
- It was! - Yes, it was!
- 昨晚很棒 - 是的,是很棒
- We just never should have done it. - I couldn't agree more.
- 我们只是永远都不要再那样了 - 再同意不过
- I am so relieved! - Great.
- 我真松了口气 - 很好
Yeah.
是的
Two mixed green salads.
两份拌蔬菜色拉
It is so nice when you can sit with someone and not have to talk. Hm?
能和人坐着而不用说话感觉真好
Most of the time, you go to bed with someone,
大多数时候你和人上床以后
then she tells you all her stories, you tell her all your stories.
她会和你讲她的事情,你和她讲你的
But with Sally and me, we'd already heard each other's stories.
但是Sally和我,我们已经听过了对方的事情
So once we went to bed, we didn't know what we were supposed to do. You know?
因此一旦我们上床后,我们不知道 该做什么,你明白吗?
Sure, Harry.
是的,Harry
I don't know.
我不知道
Maybe you get to a point in a relationship where it's too late to have sex. You know?
也许你处在那个阶段,认识太久 已经过了应该做爱的阶段,你明白吗?
Is Harry bringing anyone to the wedding?
Harry要带什么人去参加婚礼吗?
I don't think so.
我想没有吧
- Is he seeing anyone? - He was seeing this anthropologist, but...
- 他在和人交往吗? - 他本来在和一个人类学家交往,不过...
- What does she look like? - Thin, pretty, big tits.
- 她长什么样? - 很瘦,很漂亮,胸部很大
Your basic nightmare.
基本上是你的恶梦
What d'ya think?
你觉得怎么样?
Marie...
Marie...
Tell the truth.
和我说实话
It's just beautiful.
真是太漂亮了
We are gathered here today to celebrate the marriage of Marie and Jess.
今天我们齐聚一堂来 庆祝Marie和Jess的婚礼
And to consecrate their vows of matrimony.
并来见证他们的婚礼誓言
The vows they will take join their lives.
他们的誓言将与生命融为一体
The wine they will share binds all their hopes together.
他们共喝的美酒将把他们的希望联结
And by the rings they will wear,
他们将要带上的戒指
they will be known to all as husband and wife.
使他们成为丈夫和妻子
I've never seen her so happy. She's a different person.
我从来没有看到过她那么幸福 她就像另外一个人
Oh, yeah, she is. It's great, but what're we gonna do about you?
是的,她很高兴.这很好, 但是我们应该怎么对你呢?
- Me? - Hon, you wanna dance?
- 我? - Hon,想跳舞吗?
- Oh, yeah! Yeah, I do. - Excuse us.
- 哦,是的,想跳 - 失陪了
- Hi. - Hello.
- 嗨 - 哈罗
- Nice ceremony. - Beautiful.
- 很棒的结婚典礼 - 很美
Boy, the holidays are rough! Every year I try to get from Thanksgiving to New Year.
天啊,假日真不好过.每年我都想逃过 感恩节到新年的这段时间
A lot of suicides.
很多人自杀
- Would you like a pea pod with shrimp? - Thank you.
- 你想来点豆夹包虾吗? - 谢谢
- How've you been? - Fine.
- 近况如何? - 很好
- Seeing anybody? - Harry.
- 在和人交往吗? - Harry.
- What? - I don't wanna talk about this.
- 怎么了? - 我不想谈这个
- Why not? - I don't want to talk about it.
- 为什么不?
Why can't we get past this? Are we gonna carry this thing around for ever?
为什么我们不能忘掉这些? 我们要永远记得这事吗?
- Forever? It just happened! - It happened three weeks ago.
- 永远?事情才刚刚发生 - 事情发生在3星期以前
You know how a year to a person is like seven years to a dog?
你知道人的1年相当于狗的7年吗?
Yes!
是的
Is one of us supposed to be a dog in this scenario?
在这件事中我们两个要有一人当狗吗?
- Yes. - Who is the dog?
- 是的 - 谁是狗?
- You are. - I am! I am the dog!
- 你是 - 我是,我是狗
I am the dog! I...
我是狗,我...
I don't see that. You are the dog. You act like what happened didn't mean anything.
我不这样想,你才是狗. 你装着好像发生的事没意义一样
No, I don't, but why does it have to mean everything?
不,我没有.但是为什么一定要有意义?
Because it does! You know it better than anyone, cos after it happens you walk out!
因为这有意义.你比任何人都明白 因为事情结束后你逃走了
- I didn't walk out. - Sprinted is more like it.
- 我没有逃走 - 也许说逃跑出去更合适
- We both agreed it was a mistake. - The worst mistake I ever made!
- 我们都同意那是个错误 - 我犯过的最严重的错误
- What do you want from me? - Nothing!
- 你想让我怎么样? - 不怎么样
Fine! But let's just get one thing straight. I did not go over there to make love to you.
好吧!不过有件事要说清楚 我不是去那和你做爱的
But you looked at me with these weepy eyes: "Don't go home. Hold me, Harry."
但是你用含泪的眼睛看着我: "别回家,抱着我,Harry"
- What was I supposed to do? - Are you saying you took pity on me?
- 我应该怎么做? - 你是在说你是可怜我的?
- No! I was... - Fuck you!
- 不,我是... - 去你的!
Everybody, could I have your attention, please?
各位,请听我说句话
I'd like to propose a toast, to Harry and Sally.
我提议敬Harry和Sally一杯
To Harry and Sally.
敬Harry和Sally
If Marie or I had found either of them remotely attractive,
如果我和Marie发现 他们中哪个迷人的话
we would not be here today.
我们今天就不会在这里了
~ From now on our troubles will be out ofsight
<From now on our troubles will be out of sight>
~ From now on our troubles will be miles away
will be miles away>
Hi, it's me. It's the holiday season,
嗨,是我.因为假日的关系
and I thought I'd remind you that it's the season of forgiveness.
我想我要提醒你这是感恩的季节
And, although it's not widely known, it is also the season of grovelling.
同时众所周知的这也是道歉的季节
So, if you felt like calling me back,
所以如果你想回我电话的话
I'd be more than happy to do the traditional Christmas grovelling.
我会非常乐意在圣诞节道歉
Give me a call.
给我打电话
Hi, I'm not home. I'll call you right back.
嗨,我不在家.我会很快回你电话
If you're there, please pick up. I really wanna talk to you.
如果你在那,请接电话.我真的很想和你说话
The fact you're not answering leads me to believe you're either, A: not at home,
你不接电话的原因使我想到 A:不在家
B: home, but don't wanna talk to me, or C:
B:在家,但是不想和我说话
home, desperately wanna talk to me, but trapped under something heavy.
C:在家,很想和我说话,但是心里有心结
If it's either A or C, please call me back.
如果是A或者是C,请给我回电话
Obviously she doesn't wanna talk to me. What do I have to do, be hit on the head?
很明显她不想和我说话. 我能做什么?打她的头吗?
If she wants to call, she'll call. I'm through actin' like a schmuck.
如果她想打电话,她会打的 我在想自己像个傻瓜
Give me a call.
给我打电话
- Hi, Harry. - Hello. Hi! Hi!
- 嗨,Harry - 哈罗,嗨,嗨!
I didn't know that you would... That you were there.
我不知道你会... 你在家
- What're you doing? - I was just on my way out.
- 你在干什么? - 我正打算出去
Where you going?
去哪?
- What do you want, Harry? - Nothing. Nothing.
- 你想干什么,Harry? - 没什么,没什么
I... I just called to say I'm sorry.
我...我只是想说我很抱歉
OK.
好的
- I gotta go. - Wait a second. Wait... wait a second.
- 我要走了 - 等一下...等一下
What're you doin' for New Year's? Going to the Tylers' party? I don't have a date.
新年你要做什么?去参加Tylers的聚会吗? 我没有约人...
If you don't have a date, we always said we could be together for New Year's and...
如果你也没有约人,我们说过 新年可以在一起...
I can't do this any more. I am not your consolation prize.
我不能再做这种事了,我不是你的安慰奖
Goodbye.
再见
And here we are once again. The 16th annual "New Year's Rockin' Eve",
我们再度相见了,第16届"新年摇滚之夜"
coming to you live...
现在是直播...
What's so bad about this? You got Dick Clark - tradition.
这有什么不好的? 你按惯例约了Dick Clark
You got Mallomars, the greatest cookie of all time.
你有Mallomars,最棒的小甜饼
And you're about to give the Knicks their first championship since 1973.
你将为尼克斯队赢得1973年以来的第一个冠军
I don't know why I let you drag me to this.
我不知道为什么我让你把我拉到这来
This is much better. Fresh air, I have the streets all to myself.
这样好多了,新鲜空气,一个人拥有整条街
Who needs to be at a big, crowded party, pretending to have a good time?
谁想去参加人挤人的聚会,假装玩得很开心?
Plus, this is the perfect time to catch up on my window-shopping.
另外,这是开始在橱窗选购的完美时间
This is good.
这很棒
So the guy says "Read the card."
然后那个家伙说"看看卡片"
- I'm going home. - You'll never get a taxi.
- 我要回家 - 你不会叫到计程车的
Oh, God!
哦,天啊
You realise that we could never be friends.
你意识到我们永远成不了朋友
- Why not? - What I'm saying is,
- 为什么不能? - 我想说的是...
men and women can't be friends, cos the sex part always gets in the way.
男人和女人无法成为朋友, 因为总是会有性的问题掺杂进来
That's not true!
那不是真的
No man can be friends with a woman he finds attractive.
男人无法和他认为迷人的女人成为朋友
- He always wants to have sex with her. - What if they don't wanna have sex?
- 他总是想和她发生性关系 - 如果她们不想发生性关系呢?
Doesn't matter. The sex thing is already out there, so the friendship is doomed.
那也没关系.性的事情已经露出苗头了 朋友关系没戏了
And that is the end ofthe story.
这就是最后结果
- I guess we're not gonna be friends then. - Guess not.
- 我想我们不会成为朋友的 - 我也这样想
That's too bad.
真可惜
You were the only person that I knew in New York.
你是我在纽约唯一认识的一个人
- I'm going. - It's almost midnight!
- 我要走了 - 马上就是午夜了
- The thought of not kissing somebody... - I'll kiss you.
- 我在想谁也不吻... - 我会吻你
Hey, taxi! Taxi!
嘿,计程车!计程车!
Taxi!
计程车!
Shit.
见鬼
- Come on, stay. Please. - Thanks, Jess. I just... I have to go.
- 别这样,留下来 - 谢谢,Jess,我只是...我必须走
- Wait two minutes. - I'll call you tomorrow.
- 再等2分钟 - 我明天早晨给你打电话
I've been doin' a lot of thinkin', and the thing is, I love you.
我想了很多,结论是,我爱你
- What? - I love you.
- 什么? - 我爱你
- How d'you expect me to respond to this? - How about you love me, too?
- 你期待我能有什么样的回应? - 你也爱我怎么样?
- How about I'm leaving? - Doesn't what I said mean anything?
- 我要走了怎么样? - 我说的没有任何意义吗?
Sorry, Harry. I know it's New Year's Eve, I know you're feeling lonely,
对不起,Harry,我知道这是新年夜 我知道你觉得很孤单
but you just can't show up, say you love me and expect that to make it all right.
但是你不能只是出现说你爱我 期待一切都没事
- It doesn't work this way. - Well, how does it work?
- 这样不行 - 那么你想怎么样?
- I don't know, but not this way. - Then how about this way?
- 我不知道,不过不是这样 - 那么这样怎么样?
I love that you get cold when it's 71?out.
我爱你当外面71华氏度的时候还感冒
I love that it takes you 1 1 2 hours
我爱你用半个小时点三明治
I love that you get a crinkle here when you look at me like I'm nuts.
我爱你皱着眉看着傻傻的我
I love that after I spend a day with you I smell your perfume on my clothes.
我爱整天和你在一起然后 在我衣服上能闻到你的香味
And I love that you are the last person I wanna talk to before I go to sleep at night.
我还爱你是每晚睡前我最后一个想说话的人
And it's not because I'm lonely or because it's New Year's Eve.
这不是因为我孤单或者是新年夜
I came cos when you realise you wanna spend the rest of your life with someone
我来是因为如果你意识到你要 和某个人共渡余生
you want the rest of your life to start as soon as possible.
你会想你的余生能越快开始越好
You see?
你看
That is just like you, Harry.
你就是这样,Harry
You say things like that and you make it impossible for me to hate you!
你那样说话让我无法恨你
And I hate you, Harry.
我恨你,Harry
I really hate you.
我真的恨你
I hate you.
我恨你
What does this song mean? My whole life, I don't know.
这首歌是什么意思? 我一直搞不清楚
"Should auld acquaintance be forgot" - should we forget old acquaintances?
"应该忘记老熟人" 我们应该忘记老朋友吗?
Or if we forget them, should we remember them?
或者如果我们忘记了他们 我们会再想起他们吗?
Which is not possible cos we already forgot 'em!
都不可能因为我们已经忘记他们了
Maybe it just means we should remember that we forgot them, or something.
也许只是说我们应该记得 我们忘记了,或者其他什么
Anyway, it's about old friends.
总之,它是在说老朋友
The first time we met we hated each other.
我们第一次见面的时候不喜欢彼此
No, I hated you. The second time we met, you didn't even remember me.
不,你不恨我,我恨你 第二次见面你甚至都不记得我了
I did, too! I remembered you.
我当然记得,我记得你
The third time we met we became friends.
第三次见面时我们成了朋友
- We were friends for a long time. - And then we weren't.
- 我们做了很长时间朋友 - 然后我们不再是朋友了
And then we fell in love.
然后我们相爱了
- Three months later we got married. - It only took three months.
- 3个月后我们结了婚 - 只用了3个月
12 years and three months.
12年零3个月
- We had a really wonderful wedding. - It really was a beautiful wedding.
- 我们举行了非常棒的婚礼 - 那真是个漂亮的婚礼
- We had this enormous coconut cake. - Huge coconut cake with the tiers.
- 我们有很大的椰子蛋糕 - 一层一层的巨大的椰子蛋糕
And there was this very rich chocolate sauce on the side.
边上放着非常贵的巧克力沙司
Right. Cos not everybody likes it on the cake cos it makes it soggy.
没错.因为并不是所有人都喜欢沙司 会让蛋糕像用水泡过
Particularly, the coconut soaks up a lot, so it's important to keep it on the side.
显然,椰子泡过了,所以沙司放在边上是很重要的
~ Oh, if we call the whole thing off, then we must part
<Oh, if we call the whole thing off, then we must part>
~ And though if we ever part, that would break my heart
<And though if we ever part, that would break my heart>
~ They're writing songs oflove, but not for me
<They're writing songs oflove, but not for me>
~ With love to lead the way, I've found more clouds ofgrey
<With love to lead the way, I've found more clouds ofgrey>
~ Although I can't dismiss the memory ofher kiss
<Although I can't dismiss the memory ofher kiss>